<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-05-30T10:05:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Perpetual Liminality</title><subtitle>thoughts trapped in amber</subtitle><author><name>Emma Cheriegate</name></author><entry><title type="html">An Allowance of Humanity</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/allowance-humanity" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Allowance of Humanity" /><published>2025-05-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/allowance-humanity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/allowance-humanity"><![CDATA[<p>I often ponder how frequently others terrorize themselves. And by terrorize, I mean incessantly self analyze. My own cerebral capacities are subject to a recurrent onslaught of interrogation, all conducted by me. A constant questioning of the morality of my social dealings: Am I representing my character well? Am I making useful points to the conversation? Am I being kind? Am I being too kind? Do I have OCD, or pure O OCD, because I WOULDN’T WANT TO DIMINISH THE PAIN OF OTHERS WITH TRUE OCD TO MY MISAPPLICATION OF THE TERM, ahem. I think you see my point here. Then comes the more manageable, everyday criticisms: scrutinizing parts of my body that don’t measure up, rehashing the aspects of my life that have been reduced to mundanity and how much at fault I am for each of them, etc.</p>

<p>So, do others actually allow themselves an ounce of humanity? Are they genuinely more gracious toward themselves than I appear to be to myself? My prevalence of this trait and the perceived lack of it in others drives me up a wall (usually worse when I haven’t slept, have drank alcohol, eaten like shit recently, am under a lot of stress, ya know, the neurotic’s physiological checklist for mental sanity™). Sometimes, I wonder about this. Other times, I feel a deep resentment in my solitude.</p>

<p>If others do self-terrorize, though, what is the extent of their interrogation? How deeply do their questions penetrate? How much ground do they cover? Judging by the internal worlds of many I’ve gotten to know, their self-criticisms render a kind of… introspective flatness. They often lack perceptual code-switching, their questions posed along a single line of sight.
Even if I knew they did, and they shared them with similar earnestness that I do, would I even care or feel this way? How much of this perception of other people’s suffering results from loneliness? I know this whole line veers toward the unempathetic and ego-centric to even consider. But alas, am a human.</p>

<p>ANYWAY back to me disabusing myself of the notion I’m allowed an ounce of humanity. How exhausting, the idea one must be perfected. To be a performer forever center stage, auditioning for the next Broadway show. And yet in reality, it’s just a conversation with the cashier at Walmart. It’s typing a text to a friend who’s struggling. It’s ceding space to the more erratic, capricious personalities in the room. Oh, to believe oneself above reproach.</p>

<p>But, in very human fashion, these thoughts are here one moment and gone in the next. Mine just seem to return in greater frequency in some phases than others. I’ve been working at this for years, trying to rewire my neural pathways. And don’t get me wrong, this year has brought some of the greatest peace I’ve known. The swings aren’t as prevalent as they once were.</p>

<p>And yet–still, at my core, there’s always this undercurrent, a hum I can’t tune out, and I keep circling back to a Sylvia Plath quote that’s lodged itself in my hippocampus:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“What horrifies me most is the idea of being useless: well-educated, brilliantly promising, and fading out into an indifferent middle age.”</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Emma Cheriegate</name></author><category term="journal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I often ponder how frequently others terrorize themselves. And by terrorize, I mean incessantly self analyze. My own cerebral capacities are subject to a recurrent onslaught of interrogation, all conducted by me. A constant questioning of the morality of my social dealings: Am I representing my character well? Am I making useful points to the conversation? Am I being kind? Am I being too kind? Do I have OCD, or pure O OCD, because I WOULDN’T WANT TO DIMINISH THE PAIN OF OTHERS WITH TRUE OCD TO MY MISAPPLICATION OF THE TERM, ahem. I think you see my point here. Then comes the more manageable, everyday criticisms: scrutinizing parts of my body that don’t measure up, rehashing the aspects of my life that have been reduced to mundanity and how much at fault I am for each of them, etc.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/allowance-humanity.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/allowance-humanity.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Rant.Rant.Rant.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/rant-rant-rant" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rant.Rant.Rant." /><published>2025-05-19T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/rant-rant-rant</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/rant-rant-rant"><![CDATA[<p>This really is something I should do more often… Just brain dump it all out there. Idk why I don’t. I spend so much time thinking, analyzing, pondering, pontificating, that I forget just STARTING the thing is often the hardest part. But do I really forget that? I am consciously aware of it, often espousing the same advice to friends with similar struggles. Perhaps the issue is my self judgment (shocking, I know). Constantly critiquing myself for what I do or don’t do. However, I must state that the prevalence of this is beginning to lessen. I am, overall, giving vastly less amounts of consideration to the opinions of others or even my own damn negative self-assessments (since they were supplanted in my head by others). The opinions don’t matter much in the end anyway, dust to dust and ashes to ashes and all that jazz.</p>

<p>I also wonder about all the prolific writers and sentimentalists who created beautiful works of art and legacies that stretch out across several posthumous years. So many of them dulled their senses (i.e. voies in their head) with substances so that they could open the creative flood gates, thus birthing pieces like Howl and On the Road (re: see entire beat generation). Even now, it took ~2 glasses of wine to allow these words to flow. It’s not as if they don’t exist in me naturally, the stifling conundrum dies with these damn inhibitions… Always…… inhibiting me (lol). BUT I don’t want to be an alcoholic or require substances’ assistance just to create. I guess the question is, which do I care more about, my health or doing something creatively expansive with my life? The potentiality of a primarily unimpressive 85-90 years or a far shorter life with many things to show for it. Is the key just a glass or two when I need it to create? Perhaps I could avoid social drinking as a recompense (social pressure might be too high for this tradeoff, though).</p>

<p>It just felt so pointless to me (as many things often do). When you meta-analyze everything, at a certain point each instance, thought, and behavior are all reduced to absurdity anyway, such as drinking at social events with people I don’t care about who have near-zero interest in discussing anything remotely stimulating. And when they attempt, their takes are often half-baked regurgitations of something they perused on reddit while high. I’m so tired of this. I am often reduced to great weariness. I desire inspiration, to be around people who not only read but YEARN to discuss the contents of their word adventures. Those interested in partaking in salon-type parties, not spending $60 for three drinks at a bar that grants you a ticket to… speaking to the vastly uninteresting majority. I get this makes me sound arrogant. But god. My god have I spent far too much of my life apologizing for my opinions or side stepping contentious topics, or all together diminishing my light for the sake of others, their insecurity and discomfort (and for those who I don’t even have a reciprocal relationship with).</p>

<p>UGH.</p>

<p>The worst part of it all is that I know life is so much more than this. So much more than these empty and/or ultimately boring connections. So much more than the vapid self centered obsession society has cultivated with the help of social media. So much more… in general. I gotta keep trying though, what other choice do I have?</p>

<p>My life feels ultimately unfulfilling and empty punctuated by moments of brilliant closeness and connection, or adventure. But most of the time it’s just.. Dull. That’s the thing though, even if my everyday involves sitting at cafes watching people walk by in a city,,, even THAT beats being stuck in suburbia. Locked away in a little room in my version of suburban hell, only allowed out when a social event prompts my release.</p>

<p>P.S. the words of Dr. Edith Eger, holocaust survivor and psychologist, rings in my head as I reflect on all of this:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“The greatest prison that you’ll ever live inside is the prison that you create in your mind.”</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Emma Cheriegate</name></author><category term="journal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This really is something I should do more often… Just brain dump it all out there. Idk why I don’t. I spend so much time thinking, analyzing, pondering, pontificating, that I forget just STARTING the thing is often the hardest part. But do I really forget that? I am consciously aware of it, often espousing the same advice to friends with similar struggles. Perhaps the issue is my self judgment (shocking, I know). Constantly critiquing myself for what I do or don’t do. However, I must state that the prevalence of this is beginning to lessen. I am, overall, giving vastly less amounts of consideration to the opinions of others or even my own damn negative self-assessments (since they were supplanted in my head by others). The opinions don’t matter much in the end anyway, dust to dust and ashes to ashes and all that jazz.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/rant-rant-rant.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/rant-rant-rant.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Frustration of Privileged Circumstance</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/privileged-frustrations-copy" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Frustration of Privileged Circumstance" /><published>2025-05-12T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/privileged-frustrations%20copy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/privileged-frustrations-copy"><![CDATA[<p>Frustration of circumstance. I find it difficult to sit with emotions. Actually, that’s a lie. I find myself unable to allow myself to be frustrated at the state of my life. On the one hand, I understand that my perception of this sentience and the world is limited to my own experience, and drowning under one foot of water vs a hundred feet of water is still drowning, and that the only way beyond is through, and that no justice is done in minimizing my own pain. But I just find fully ingratiating these realities into my subconscious to be..well..so.. difficult.</p>

<p>How can I, in good conscience, allow myself such a privilege as to wallow in my grievances? To take stock of the downsides in my (by most degrees) cushy life and wager complaints? I know what you’re saying. I know. Literally, shut up. I hear you loud and clear: disallowing yourself the ability to feel and accept the shittiness of your human condition does not help, nor do any of my justifications for this pitiful self-invalidation.</p>

<p>I make mental checklists. These lists account myriad sufferings of others who were dealt a far worse hand than I, those who live(d) in abject poverty, experience(d) heinous acts of violence in the name of domination, genocide, being orphaned at a young age, living in a region with greater tumult and lesser privilege, not being able-bodied, etc, etc, etc (ad nauseum). Is full acceptance of myself so unrealistic, so far out of reach?</p>

<p>I know where this comes from. Reiterated assertions of my own lack of worth throughout adolescence, my surroundings being comprised of incessant commanding narcissistic personalities, and my own annoyed disillusionment with the tremendous lack of empathy I notice within human communities (and individuals). But STILL. I could list a thousand reasons in favor of self-acceptance, yet it hasn’t sunk in.</p>

<p>I guess everything takes time. I’ve been doing mindfulness meditation, healthy lifestyle, boundary setting for a while. Each within timelines of varying fits and starts. I understand the rewiring of my neural pathways takes time, especially after a lifetime of being wired in the opposite direction. Neural pathways don’t care how insightful you are. They care about repetition, practice, and patience. Alas, I am mindfully aware that the frustration seeps in deeper at night time. And yet, dually aware that everything is better after sleep and a snack.</p>

<p>Well, almost everything.</p>]]></content><author><name>Emma Cheriegate</name></author><category term="journal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Frustration of circumstance. I find it difficult to sit with emotions. Actually, that’s a lie. I find myself unable to allow myself to be frustrated at the state of my life. On the one hand, I understand that my perception of this sentience and the world is limited to my own experience, and drowning under one foot of water vs a hundred feet of water is still drowning, and that the only way beyond is through, and that no justice is done in minimizing my own pain. But I just find fully ingratiating these realities into my subconscious to be..well..so.. difficult.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/docked-boat.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/docked-boat.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Jealousy as the Ultimate Existential/Social CockBlock</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jealousy-existential-cockblock-copy" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jealousy as the Ultimate Existential/Social CockBlock" /><published>2025-05-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jealousy-existential-cockblock%20copy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jealousy-existential-cockblock-copy"><![CDATA[<p>How often are we cognizant of the source of our jealousy? How often are we dually aware of the sensation felt, and the original insecurity within ourselves that caused it? Envy and jealousy provoke actions of poor taste, causing us to act passive aggressively or in a downright cruel manner. Displays of this deficient character reveal themselves through both subtle criticisms and ostentatious displays of hate. Or on an even less discernible scale, they can be carried out through simple neglect to action.</p>

<p>An example of this could be a general refraining from communicated niceties, such as compliments/words of praise. Eschewing from complimenting may feel like a simple evasion to the perpetrator, but is nonetheless rooted in a sinister intention (or lack of intent), and has potential negative effects for both parties. For the jealous individual, possible opportunities for human connection and personal (mental/emotional/psychological) growth. For the other, the expression could have been sorely needed.</p>

<p>Insecurity causes people to withhold verbalized or expressed admiration. In some instances this is excused by a purported “lack of creativity” in eloquence. However, this neglects the fact that there is no requirement of complexity in complimenting. It is important to note here that compliments mean of any variety, whether it is something as simple as “that was a wonderful speech!” or “you are pretty!” Use of this defaulted argument reveals how deeply rooted the insecurity is.</p>

<p>From an uninvolved perspective, it seems as if the individual is asserting their stance as if their entire sense of self depends on it. As if expressing commendation could cause the faulty foundation with which their self esteem rests on to crumble or dissipate entirely. Of course, insecurity is not the only reason a person could abstain in this kindness, but it just so happens to be alarmingly common with the pertinent group. Moreover, it is almost amusing how the perpetrator’s brain will invest immense effort to excuse its action, even resorting to self-absolutions as contradictory as a lack of energy or time to dole out.</p>

<p>How much does it cost a person to say something nice, to expend a sliver of effort to type or speak an additional sentence of warmth to another? A popular dissenting evasion tends to be, “Well I just don’t have the time for it!” Wrong. We are in total control of how we invest our mental and physical energy. If one or any of said efforts happen to feel like an obligation, and therefore make us feel helpless at the hands of them, well, it is important to remember that we are the ones attributing the obligatory title to the task. If another involved party makes us feel pressured into perceiving it as an obligation, well we don’t have to adopt their view. School, family, work, all the things that people usually point to in excusing a lack of effort, are all still choices.</p>

<p>Now I am not some asshole advocating to forsake our families, give up on school, or forgo professional endeavors. But rather, to learn how to utilize our time better, and more importantly, to stop using a lack of “time” as an excuse for inaction or neglectance. To stop using it as a shield that protects face in social scenarios when we don’t want to be honest about the matter at hand.</p>

<p>Furthermore, even with obligatory tasks, we in the Privileged World of the West™ have copious amounts of free-time (comparatively speaking to those focused on the lowest level of Maslow’s hierarchy: survival). The best illustration of the humorously disparaging contradiction to our temporal excuses is use of social media: “Sorry, I just don’t have the time” <em>scrolls on social media for 3 hours of the day</em>. We are so afraid of being honest, because we want to protect that image the person has of us, to not come off as if we don’t care. But it isn’t that we don’t care! We do! Just not enough to devote our time to it… It is an excuse for our own inaction. We must be careful of the rational mind… For it will validate any of our tendencies, toxic or not, for the sake of our own comfort (and in apt support of cognitive dissonance).</p>

<p>Another possible justification for abstaining from expressing compliments often heard are, “well they are just so confident, they don’t need to hear compliments from me.” The fuck? What human needs compliments? A need is something necessary for biological survival. Those that rely on positive affirmations exist on an ineffective form of fuel, for as long as their reliance on it remains, they will be perpetually broken inside. (Trust me, I was that person). Regardless, niceties and expressions of our admiration, no matter how small, are just kind hearted to convey, and end up having a positive effect for both parties. There are endless studies on how focusing on compassion and doing things for others leads to more substantive happiness than hedonistic self centered ventures to achieve the same means.</p>

<p>As previously stated, no one should rest their sense of pride atop external validation. But this does not negate the fact that words do have a huge impact on people. Communicating appreciation or a special liking of a part of someone can make their day, week, month. Think about the times someone sacrificed just 30 seconds of their day to impart kind verbiage to you. How did it feel? Now think, why would we not want to perpetuate that feeling for others? Thoughtful utterances like that have immense power. The receiver could have been aching for even the smallest friendliness, their lives devoid of kind words from others. They could be on the precipice of a mental breakdown, or on a more extreme edge. Words have the power to change our internal perceptions of things. This is evident in school, our worldview tends to expand as a result of hearing the words and articulations of people wiser than us. And the same goes for those kinder than us.</p>

<p>Jealousy clouds our perception in a variety of ways, but a special one to note is that it causes us to forsake reflection. We can become negligent of the individual efforts that preceded the obtainment of the desirable characteristic that made us jealous: all of the work, life experiences, writing, dedication that went into its cultivation in the person. We assume they were born that way, or it was a product of their environment, or they had X personality trait so attaining the other one was easy. When in actuality, almost everything that is good or worthwhile comes as a result of sacrifice, not happenstance. Most of the things that amaze us in others did not come about by simply existing. Sure, some are born into environments that are more privileged from the start. But the way we frame our sufferings significantly determines future outcomes and interactions with the world. Google James R. Doty and read about his early life and subsequent work for an example.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“Nothing of me is original. I am the combined effort of everyone I’ve ever known.”<br />
— Chuck Palahniuk</p>
</blockquote>

<p>In the end, all jealousy and judgment does is inhibit us. They prevent us from seeing another person’s point of view, and keeps us stuck, experiencing the world through a self centered perspective. The worst part of this is that it obstructs us from our shared goal of mutual understanding and human connection, which is what most of humanity truly aches for internally. Adopting an envious lens causes our focus to narrow. We miss out on the nuance in the periphery, what lies beyond our immediate gaze. The person we didn’t speak to, the individual we shot a glare at, the human we avoided interacting with could very well have changed our life. They could have been a potential friend, teacher, or lover. They could have offered a perspective or shared an experience that inspired us to change our own. They could have taught us something new, or on the most basic intrinsic level, we would have engaged in a genuine human exchange. And the thing that could have altered our course into that direction? A simple hello, a radiant friendly smile, or even, dare I say, a compliment.</p>]]></content><author><name>Emma Cheriegate</name></author><category term="journal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How often are we cognizant of the source of our jealousy? How often are we dually aware of the sensation felt, and the original insecurity within ourselves that caused it? Envy and jealousy provoke actions of poor taste, causing us to act passive aggressively or in a downright cruel manner. Displays of this deficient character reveal themselves through both subtle criticisms and ostentatious displays of hate. Or on an even less discernible scale, they can be carried out through simple neglect to action.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/jealousy.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/jealousy.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Graduate School Stole Something From Me</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/grad-school-stole" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Graduate School Stole Something From Me" /><published>2025-04-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-04-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/grad-school-stole</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/grad-school-stole"><![CDATA[<p>Graduate school stole something from me. This “something” was an amalgamation of numerous smaller things, diverse yet unified, their collective loss representing my final shred of innocence.</p>

<p>A torrent of thoughts rush forth, spilling over one another, each striving eagerly toward the open whitespace of my computer screen. The multitudinous nature of my thoughts, coupled with my desire to share them, often overwhelms me, particularly as my internal editor stands ever-ready, quick to prune and polish even my most sparing word choices. I battle an incessant critique: scrutinizing each sentence’s logical coherence, obsessing over maintaining the reader’s interest, and burdening myself with the expectation of articulated brilliance. What an immense and ultimately pointless pressure to impose on oneself, regardless of skill. As if skill was ever truly a prerequisite at the outset of any endeavor. The daily headlines from the highest echelons of government in the U.S. and my own interactions with peers and supervisors in graduate school provide ample evidence to the contrary.</p>

<h2 id="the-cost-of-academia">The Cost of Academia</h2>

<p>In graduate school, my advisor was particularly petulant, emotionally capricious, and obsessed with control and power. She reacted extremely negatively when challenged or questioned, even if the questions were innocuous, publicly berating and embarrassing lab students, stonewalling all communication for weeks at a time, and using emotional intimidation to prevent further clarification or engagement. Frequently, she resorted to grandstanding, fabricating answers rather than admitting uncertainty, which only obfuscated the subject and her own morality further.</p>

<p>Increasingly, it seems evident that the most critical factor for flourishing within our communities is not genuine competence or merit, but rather the connections we hold. Vast swaths of unqualified individuals occupy positions at society’s highest levels not due to legitimate skill or expertise, but through their proficiency at playing the social game. The pursuit and achievement of status drive many human behaviors: status encompassing likability, acceptance, and social safety.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“The urge for rank is ineradicable. It’s the secret goal of our lives, to win status for ourselves and our game - and gain as much of it over you and you and you as we can. It’s how we make meaning. It’s how we make identity.”</p>

  <p>— <em>Will Storr, The Status Game</em></p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="people-pleasing--deception">People-Pleasing &amp; Deception</h2>

<p>Is it true, then, that our inherent nature is fundamentally driven by a desire to be viewed favorably, even superiorly, compared to others? I once held the perhaps naïve belief that goodness formed the foundation for many people’s actions. My last remaining piece of innocence was my deluded conviction that individuals operate predominantly on ethics of honesty, transparency, and kindness, not universally, but at least in earnest reciprocity.</p>

<p>Graduate school—and the way my brain adapted to those and subsequent experiences—destroyed that notion for me. However, this deterioration of my idealistic perceptions began long before, though I didn’t recognize it then, perhaps because I too participated through habitual people-pleasing.</p>

<p>Even those whose behaviors appear kind on the surface might harbor ulterior motives. Consider people-pleasers, a self-righteous and endlessly justifying group (even if only to ourselves). This identity, although outwardly benevolent, frequently masks dishonesty. Such actions typically stem from fear. Fear of negative reactions, loss of community, or adverse perceptions of the self. These behaviors are fundamentally deceptive: by withholding truth, we deny others the chance to see situations clearly and make informed decisions regarding their relationships with us.</p>

<h2 id="the-weight-of-obfuscation">The Weight of Obfuscation</h2>

<p>Is the path to hell paved with good intentions, or are we fooling ourselves in assuming intentions were ever genuinely good? This is the crux of my current frustration—the constant obfuscation of true intent. People frequently suppress their reactions, moderate facial expressions, code-switch depending on their audience, and meticulously select their words. Certainly, some level of caution is a sign of maturity and wisdom. Pausing to reflect before voicing haughty opinions, withholding our deepest secrets from strangers, or refraining from burdening already-overwhelmed friends are acts of genuine care.</p>

<p>Yet, at times, such guarded behavior emerges from fear and cowardice, defense mechanisms that, though understandable, render life exhausting and irritating.</p>

<h2 id="seeking-honesty">Seeking Honesty</h2>

<p>In reflecting on my own similar behaviors, I realize they originated in deferential naïveté and a lack of self-esteem. True honesty, not devoid of kindness or situational awareness, requires courage. Expressing how we genuinely feel ultimately frees us, enabling authentic human connections. Through openness, vulnerabilities previously perceived as weaknesses become avenues for meaningful relationships. Honesty facilitates our own growth and reveals common ground that binds us to others, transcending fear and paving the path toward genuine connection.</p>

<p>Thus, the question I’m continually left pondering (as evidenced by my persistent thought patterns) is how are these behaviors influenced by our brain’s internal mechanisms?</p>]]></content><author><name>Emma Cheriegate</name></author><category term="journal" /><category term="documentation" /><category term="sample" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Graduate school stole something from me. This “something” was an amalgamation of numerous smaller things, diverse yet unified, their collective loss representing my final shred of innocence.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/grad-school-stole.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/grad-school-stole.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">I’m Still Not Sure Where to Go from Here</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/not-sure-where-to-go" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I’m Still Not Sure Where to Go from Here" /><published>2025-04-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-04-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/not-sure-where-to-go</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/not-sure-where-to-go"><![CDATA[<p>I once told myself that one way to orient amidst a multitude of feelings was to put pen to page. For years, journaling has reminded me of the power of writing—of giving shape to emotions through words. It’s like unplugging the drain of an overfilled bathtub: letting out just enough to prevent the spill.</p>

<p>I return often to this state of emotional overwhelm. I imagine most people who choose to face their feelings know it well (those who avoid them, obviously, don’t).</p>

<p>But no matter how much I write, I doubt any number of words—any attempt to articulate this particular grief—could ever drain the bathtub of my missing them.</p>

<p>They were my intellectual solace. When we first met, I was astounded by the breadth of their perspective and the depth of their intelligence—spanning disciplines, social contexts, ways of thinking. They balanced wit, empathy, and compassionate accountability. With effortless grace, they called people out on their contradictions in a way that invited reflection, not shame. They did this for me.</p>

<p>I don’t think I’ll ever get over the loss. Their existence was hope. Hope that making a meaningful contribution to the world was possible. That it had a point. Their presence, their continued survival, meant others like them were out there. They were proof that brilliance and care could coexist. And when I learned they were gone, I lost that hope, in a way.</p>

<p>I never met anyone like them again.</p>

<p>I flew across the country searching for minds and souls like theirs. It’s one of the reasons I turned to graduate school. Even though we weren’t in touch, the idea that others like them existed kept me going. I dedicated myself to finding them—but after three years, I hadn’t. No one compared.</p>

<p>They were my oasis. A sounding board for the irrational, the nonsensical, the deeply human contradictions I witnessed everywhere. Their friendship made the dishonesty and dissonance in the world more bearable. And without their presence, I’d be remiss not to admit: I’m still struggling to find that hope again.</p>]]></content><author><name>Emma Cheriegate</name></author><category term="journal" /><category term="documentation" /><category term="sample" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I once told myself that one way to orient amidst a multitude of feelings was to put pen to page. For years, journaling has reminded me of the power of writing—of giving shape to emotions through words. It’s like unplugging the drain of an overfilled bathtub: letting out just enough to prevent the spill.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/empty-bench.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/empty-bench.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>